export const GENERALKNOWLEDGEINARTSA2018 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The shape of an object describes its",
A: "beauty.",
B: "content.",
C: "form.",
D: "style.",
answer: "C. form.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The design process begins with",
A: "analysis.",
B: "identification.",
C: "investigation.",
D: "solution.",
answer: "C. investigation.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Vanishing point can be located on the",
A: "background",
B: "eye level.",
C: "cone of vision.",
D: "foreground",
answer: "C. cone of vision.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. A piece of material used in making mosaic is known as",
A: "montage.",
B: "tesser",
C: "template.",
D: "support.",
answer: "B. tesser",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. A visual tension created in painting is termed",
A: "dominance.",
B: "rhythm.",
C: "opposition.",
D: "stability.",
answer: "C. opposition.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of the following is a quality of a creative person?",
A: "friendliness",
B: "originality",
C: "quietness",
D: "truancy",
answer: "B. originality",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. An outstanding feature of an African art is that it is",
A: "functional.",
B: "primitive.",
C: "uneducative.",
D: "unproductive.",
answer: "A. functional.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Ancient Greeks painted mainly on",
A: "temples.",
B: "tombs.",
C: "walls.",
D: "vases.",
answer: "D. vases.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. How can actual texture be created in a work of art?",
A: "By looking at surfaces of materials",
B: "By organizing lines and dots",
C: "By photographic techniques",
D: "By using the impasto technique",
answer: "D. By using the impasto technique",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. A good composition must have one of the following sets of qualities.",
A: "Lines, dots, volume",
B: "Unity, proportion, balance",
C: "Shape, texture, colour",
D: "Volume, space, plane",
answer: "B. Unity, proportion, balance",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Rendition of soft tones are easily made with",
A: "BB pencils.",
B: "HH pencils.",
C: "HB pencils.",
D: "6 B pencils.",
answer: "D. 6 B pencils.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The correct way to draw a cuboid is by applying",
A: "aerial perspective",
B: "angular perspective",
C: "colour perspective.",
D: "parallel perspective.",
answer: "B. angular perspective",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following steps best suits the procedure of appreciation?  \nI. Technical qualities  \nII. Inventory of items  \nIII. Interpretation of work  \nIV. Identification of work",
A: "I, II, III and IV",
B: "III, IV, II and I",
C: "II, I, IV and III",
D: "IV, II, I and III",
answer: "D. IV, II, I and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Ibeji and Akuaba figures are both",
A: "easy to carve.",
B: "made from soft materials.",
C: "fertility figures.",
D: "made in the same country.",
answer: "C. fertility figures.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The art of plaiting and braiding human hair is known as",
A: "coiffure.",
B: "com-row.",
C: "dansinkran",
D: "mpoas",
answer: "A. coiffure.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following is a ceramist?",
A: "Akpo Teye",
B: "R. Ekem",
C: "Ofei Nyarko",
D: "Saka Acquaye",
answer: "A. Akpo Teye",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The Minsereh was made by the",
A: "Bambar",
B: "Bawong",
C: "Dagon.",
D: "Mende.",
answer: "D. Mende.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The Polynesians produced high quality fabric called",
A: "Akwete.",
B: "Jav",
C: "Tap",
D: "Wayang.",
answer: "C. Tap",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Prehistoric art survived because they",
A: "are always admired by people.",
B: "tell the story of the past.",
C: "show man’s talent.",
D: "were made away from the weather.",
answer: "D. were made away from the weather.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Renaissance art placed emphasis on",
A: "architectural expeditions.",
B: "geometric treatment of an object.",
C: "the importance of the individual.",
D: "the style of painting.",
answer: "C. the importance of the individual.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of these shapes gives a feeling of monotony?",
A: "Hexagon",
B: "Pentagon",
C: "Square",
D: "Triangle",
answer: "C. Square",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Full awareness of the qualities in what we see is termed as",
A: "appreciation.",
B: "criticism.",
C: "creativity.",
D: "judgment.",
answer: "A. appreciation.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. In pricing an artifact, it is important to consider the",
A: "beauty of the product.",
B: "durability of the product.",
C: "cost of production.",
D: "value of the product.",
answer: "C. cost of production.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The area where the artist executes his painting is the",
A: "negative space.",
B: "picture plane.",
C: "picture frame.",
D: "positive space.",
answer: "B. picture plane.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The four families of typeface are",
A: "italic, calligraphy, block and spur.",
B: "prototype, trajan, roman and arabi",
C: "roman, italic, gothic and text.",
D: "serif, text, gothic and Latin.",
answer: "C. roman, italic, gothic and text.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following is a shading technique?",
A: "Colouring",
B: "Enamelling",
C: "Dyeing",
D: "Hatching",
answer: "D. Hatching",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Dominance is achieved in a picture when",
A: "emphasis is placed on one part against the other.",
B: "the background is painted with chromatic colours.",
C: "the colours are used in their raw state.",
D: "the elements are arranged in symmetric balance.",
answer: "A. emphasis is placed on one part against the other.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Masks worn during initiation rites are worn to instill",
A: "discipline in the initiates.",
B: "fear in women and children.",
C: "greatness in the youth.",
D: "instability in the community.",
answer: "A. discipline in the initiates.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of these options symbolizes newness?",
A: "Blue",
B: "Brown",
C: "Green",
D: "Grey",
answer: "C. Green",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Visual equilibrium in a picture is termed",
A: "balance.",
B: "rhythm.",
C: "dominance.",
D: "stability.",
answer: "A. balance.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Black as a pigment is described as",
A: "grey.",
B: "neutral.",
C: "shade",
D: "tint.",
answer: "B. neutral.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Pointillism is also referred to as",
A: "Divisionism.",
B: "Futurism.",
C: "Fauvism.",
D: "Illusionism.",
answer: "A. Divisionism.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. A picture created by pasting scraps of paper on a support is called",
A: "montage.",
B: "mosaic",
C: "papiercolle",
D: "papier-mâché.",
answer: "C. papiercolle",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The cireperdue process is associated with",
A: "batik production.",
B: "bronze casting.",
C: "bead production.",
D: "screen printing.",
answer: "B. bronze casting.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following is a planographic process?",
A: "Acquatint",
B: "Lithography",
C: "Gravure",
D: "Messotint",
answer: "B. Lithography",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Squeegee is a tool used mainly in",
A: "Ceramics.",
B: "Picture making.",
C: "Graphic design.",
D: "Sculpture.",
answer: "C. Graphic design.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Grey haft is made white by",
A: "bleaching.",
B: "scouring.",
C: "dyeing.",
D: "sizing.",
answer: "A. bleaching.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Identify the basic materials for drawing.",
A: "Colours and papers",
B: "Pallets and rulers",
C: "Erasers and pencils",
D: "Papers and brushes",
answer: "C. Erasers and pencils",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The main material used for ancient Japanese sculpture was",
A: "clay.",
B: "plastic",
C: "stone.",
D: "wax.",
answer: "C. stone.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The palace art of Benin empire was mostly made of",
A: "Brass, silver and gold",
B: "Gold, ivory and wood",
C: "Bronze, clay and ivory",
D: "Wood, clay and silver",
answer: "A. Brass, silver and gold",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]